

#### **BEKRY MOHAMMED**

#### **DATA ENGINEER**

A Data engineer with excellent programming skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and python. I posses a very good understanding of databases, frameworks and version control. - I have 12 years of experience in Engineering, teamwork and collaboration with international teams. I am excited to join a dynamic software developer team in the tech sector so that I can advance and make a difference.

bekrye@gmail.com Mobile: +251944984434

Addis Ababa 🙇 25.12.1984, in Tigray, Ethiopia

- GitHub repository: https://github.com/bky201/

- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bekrv-mohammed/

# **EDUCATION**

April 2023 - November 2023 Diploma in Full stack Software Development

Code Institute, GmbH, Berlin, Germany

Full Stack Software Development

September 2019 - July 2021 MASTER OF SCIENCE in Data Engineering

Jacobs University Bremen, Germany

- All aspects of data engineering and ML process, including building ETL pipelines, and

preprocessing

- Selected courses: Big Databases and Cloud Services, Machine learning, Data Visualization

October 2003 - July 2008

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, Electrical Engineering

Jimma University, Ethiopia

-signal processing, computer programming, computer networks, communication engineering

#### SKILLS

Programming: HTML / CSS / Java-script / Typescript / Python / Node.js OS: Linux / Windows / Shell Script / Bash (Unix Shell) / Linux Commands Database: SQL / MySQL / PostgreSQL / MongoDB / Cassandra

Version control: Git / Github

Django / jQuery / Bootstrap Frameworks:

Library: ReactJS / Redux

### **DATA ENGINEERING PROJECTS**

\* Designing and implementing various concepts and components in the data engineering.

GitHub - https://github.com/bky201/Data Engineering Capstone Project.git

Technologies used - relational databases, NoSQL data stores, data warehouses, data pipelines, Linux shell scripting, SQL, Python

\* Implementing AI/ML models for various data analysis methods and compare the result of each implementation for sales prediction. GitHub - https://github.com/bky201/Data-Analysis-study.git

Technologies used - Python, Git, GitHub

\* Implementing AI/ML models using auto-encoders to compress and reconstruct input data on various types of images and texts datasets. GitHub - https://github.com/bky201/Auto-Encoders

Technologies used - Python, Git, GitHub

- \* CI/CD Pipeline: GitLab https://github.com/bky201/ci-cd-gitlab.git
- \* Docker and Kubernetes https://github.com/bky201/docker-kubernets.git

# **FULL STACK PROJECTS**

- \* My-events: Full Stack website for sharing events photos.- GitHub https://github.com/bky201/events-api.git Technologies used - HTML5, CSS, React, Python, Django rest framework, Bootstrap, Unittest, Git, Github, Heroku
- \* Hotel Room Booking: Full Stack website for Hotel Booking system.- GitHub https://github.com/bky201/HotelBooking.git Technologies used - HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Django, Bootstrap, Unittest, Git, Github, Heroku

## **HACKATHON PROJECTS**

- \* CODE WARS: THE HACKATHON STRIKES BACK Hackathon in May 2024 organized for 6 days by Code Institute.
- Collaborated with a team to develop "The\_Fork\_Awakens" quiz game app.

Github - https://github.com/bky201/the fork awakens.git

Technologies used - HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Figma, Fontawesome, Git, Github, Netlify

- \* CUPID'S CODE QUEST Hackathon in February 2024 organized for 6 days by Code Institute.
- Collaborated with a team to develop "The Love Bugs app" that enables couples to unite together. Github - https://github.com/bky201/the-cupid-bugs.git
- Technologies used HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Django, Bootstrap, Balsamiq, PostgreSQL, Git, Github, Heroku
- \* BUDGET BUSTERS Hackathon in January 2024 organized for 6 days by Code Institute.
  - Collaborated with a team to develop an app that enables users to track their finances efficiently.

Github - https://github.com/bky201/jan24-hackathon.git

Technologies used - HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Django, Bootstrap, Miro, PostgreSQL, DALL.E 3, Git, Github, Heroku

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

January 2022 – January 2023 Gorillas Operation Rider

# Gorillas Operation Germany GmbH & Co KG Bremen, Germany

- Delivery of Goods to customers.
- Product quality and expiry date checking.
- Ware house product organization and storage.

September 2021 – December 2021 Fulfillment Center Associate

# Amazon Logistik Achim GmbH Bremen, Germany

- Inbound dock, products distribution.
- Stowing and storing items inside pods.
- Bar code scanning and product checking

July 2020 – July 2021 Working Student

#### **DPD Deutschland GmbH VZ**

Bremen, Germany

- Inbound dock, products distribution.
- Outbound dock storing items inside container.

September 2017 – July 2019

**Electrical Engineer** 

# EDNA MALL HTS PLC Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Performed data analysis and created visualization dashboards.
- Plan and monitor project progress.
- Prepared weekly progress reports

January 2014 – September 2017

Freelancer

# China Railway Construction Engineering

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Supervision project execution on site.
- Prepared material request for site execution.
- Tested and Handed over completed projects.

March 2009 – June 2013 Electrical Engineer

# Alsaad General Contracting Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

- Installed electrical systems for Automation of Buildings.
- Installed Fire alarm and Voice evacuation systems.
- Tested and Handed over completed networking systems.

#### CERTIFICATION

- Coursera: Introduction to NoSQL Databases ( 18 hours)
- Coursera: Hands-on Introduction to Linux Commands and Shell Scripting (14 hours)
- Coursera: Introduction to Relational Databases (RDBMS) ( 15 hours)
- Udemy: Agile Fundamental Including Scrum and Kanban 2021 (4.5 hours)
- Udemy : Cloud Computing with AWS Amazon Web Services (10 hours)
- Udemy: Docker and Kubernetes The Practical Guide (23.5 hours)
- Udemy : Build React Node AWS MERN Stack Real Estate Marketplace App (19 hours)
- Udemy: The Complete JavaScript Course 2023: From Zero to Expert! ( 69 hours)
- Udemy : The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp (65.5 hours)
- Udemy: Web Scraping in Python BeautifulSoup, Selenium and Scrapy 2022 ( 9 hours)
- Udemy: Complete React Developer in 2023 (with Redux, Hooks, GraphQL) (42.5 hours)

# **LANGUAGES**

English: Expert German: Intermediate Tigrinya: Native Amharic: Expert Arabic: Expert

#### **INTEREST**

- Playing football: Engaging in the exhilarating sport of football provides an active outlet for physical fitness, teamwork, and the joy of competing.
- Watching movies: The captivating experience of watching movies allows for immersion in different narratives, Emotions and visual storytelling.
- Spending time with friends: Sharing moments and creating cherished memories with friends fosters connections, laughter, and a sense of belonging in a supportive social circle.